＜綱手 : ネジとナルトが 顔を上げると➡
Neji and Naruto looked up…
そこには
今までと異なる空間があった＞
and found themselves in
a space different from before…
(ネジ)貴様が
今度の事件の仕掛け人か。
Are you the one responsible
for all of this?
Hey!
(ナルト)おい こら！
Let Kakashi Sensei and everyone
from the Hidden Leaf go!
カカシ先生とか 木ノ葉の人たちとか
返しやがれ！
Or you're gonna get it!
さもねえと
ひでえ目に遭わすぞ！
ナルト その男から離れろ。
邪魔すんなってばよ！
Naruto! Get away from him!
Don't butt in!
I'm about to settle this right now!
今 こいつと
話をつけてるところなんだからよ。
Look at his eyes.
そいつの眼を見ろ。
え？
Huh?
白眼！
The Byakugan?
お前の手に負える相手じゃない。
くっ…。
You're no match for him.
貴様は 何者だ。
Who are you?
なぜ 白眼を持つ？
How do you possess the Byakugan?
まさか…
日向に縁ある者なのか？
Don't tell me…
Do you have ties to the Hyuga?
あの土煙を見るがいい。
Look at the cloud of dust…
お前たちの仲間が
この里で行った所業の結果だ。
Your comrades did that.
何があった。
What happened?
この里の童たちの命より
自分たちの掟を優先する…。
They put their village's rules before
the lives of the children.
The Hidden Leaf hasn't changed
a bit in all these years.
相変わらず 木ノ葉隠れの里は➡
昔から
何一つ 変わっていないんだな。
貴様に 木ノ葉の何がわかる。
What do you know about
the Hidden Leaf?
ああ わかるさ。
Oh, I know plenty.
In fact, I know more than
anyone presently here.
少なくとも
ここにいる誰よりもな。
俺に ついてくるがいい。
Follow me…
日向ネジ。
Neji Hyuga.
木ノ葉隠れの里が
ひた隠しにしてきた真実を➡
If you want to discover
the ugly truth
the Hidden Leaf has covered up…
知りたかったらな。
《何なんだ？
何言ってんだよ あいつ》
What?
What is he talking about?
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Masked Man
Komichi!
(アシタバ)コミチ～！
(シカマル)影首縛りの術 成功！
Shadow Strangle Jutsu, complete.
(弥彦)お前ら…。
You guys…
(長門)来てくれたのか。
…came.
Hurry, get the child!
早く あの子を！
(いの)えっ!?
Damn it!
クッソ！
うっ！
コミチ～！
Komichi!
Ino!
いの！
Ninja Art: Mind Transfer Jutsu!
忍法 心転身の術！
No!
やだ～！
いの！
Nagato, go!
長門！ 捜せ！
Hurry and find that monster!
早く あの化け物を見つけ出せ！
(シカマル)任せろ！
Leave it to us!
こいつの精神が
あの子の体に入った。
Her psyche has entered
the child's body.
そんなことが…。
That's…possible?
いののやつ 中で踊ってやがるぜ。
Ino's probably jumping
around inside of it.
小南！
Konan!
Now!
今だ！
いや～っ！
うっ。
いの。
Ino!
Komichi!
(アシタバ)コミチ！
(コミチ)お兄ちゃん！
Big Brother!
チョウジ！
Choji!
(チョウジ)ブハ～！
ハァ…。
うわ～っ！
(２人)あっ！
うわっ！
ぶへ～っ。
もう！ 危うくバラバラになるところ
だったじゃないか！
Hey! I almost got blown up!
《なんだ？ あいつの眼は》
What's up with his eye?
(２人)お母ちゃ～ん！
– Mommy!
Ashitaba! Komichi!
(カヤ)アシタバ コミチ！
もうあんたたちは。
ごめんよ ごめんね。
You two—!
I'm sorry, so sorry!
マシマ様がお守りくださったんだね。
あんたたちを。
Lord Mashima protected you…
the both of you!
ううん 違うよ。
No, it was the people over there…
あのお兄ちゃんと
お姉ちゃんたちが。
Where did they—?
Tell us…
聞かせろよ。
最初から本気で 命を取り合おう➡
Right from the beginning,
I didn't get the feeling that
you wanted to kill us.
って気配じゃなかった。
何かをさせようとしたんだろ？
You were trying to get us
to do something.
(弥彦)お前は残念な野郎だった。
I was wrong about you.
木ノ葉の命令には逆らえない。
You'd never disobey an order
from the Hidden Leaf…
木ノ葉の掟の中でしか
生きられない。
You can't live outside
the rules of the Hidden Leaf.
そんな野郎だと 俺は見定めた。
I assumed you were
that kind of shinobi…
だが 思い違いだったようだ。
But I was very wrong.
お前たちは 自来也様が
俺たちにしてくれたように➡
Through your actions,
you demonstrated what
Jiraiya Sensei taught us to do.
木ノ葉の里以外の者でも
力になってやる 助けてやると➡
You used your powers
to help people in need,
even if they aren't from
the Hidden Leaf…
行動で示してくれた。
(長門)嬉しかったんだ。
あの時 来てくれて。
I was really happy that
you came back.
(小南)あなたたちのおかげで
私たちも助かった。
Thanks to you,
we were saved too.
ん… 冗談だろ？
Are you joking?
(弥彦)お前たちだけでも
一緒にやらないか？
Would the three of you like
to work with us?
どういうこと？
What are they talking about?
こいつらが
アスマ先生をさらったんじゃないの？
Didn't they abduct Asuma Sensei?
あぁ。
Yeah…
仲間になれとは言わない。
I'm not asking you to join us…
木ノ葉にいてもかまわない。
I don't care if you stay with the Leaf.
だが 自来也様のように
国から国へ渡り➡
We can travel from nation to nation,
like Jiraiya Sensei, and cross over
meaningless borders…
くだらない境界線をまたいで➡
俺たちは自由だってことを
世界に見せつけてやろうぜ。
Let's show the world
that we're free!
どういう意味？
What does that mean?
そうだね
いまいち意味不明だけど…。
Well, it's kinda unclear…
つまり チーム・ジライヤってことだろ？
In other words,
be like Team Jiraiya, right?
志を１つにしたいんだ
お前たちと。
I want our aspirations
to be united…with you.
まだ アスマたちの行方を➡
You haven't even told us where
Asuma Sensei and the others are…
聞かせてもらってない
この現状で➡
そこまで無邪気にはなれねえな。
We're not that naïve…
First, you have to help us
get Asuma Sensei back.
まず アスマ先生を救い出すのに
協力してくれなきゃ。
あぁ そうだね。
Yeah, that's right.
そのことに関しては
力になれない。
We can't help you with that.
お前たち以外に
うごめいている者がいるんだろ？
There's someone else
pulling the strings, isn't there?
この面接試験だって➡
This "test" doesn't seem
to be your idea either.
お前らが段取ったものじゃ
ねえようだしな。
すまない 僕たちも
詳しくは聞かされてないんだ。
Sorry. They haven't given us
the details.
フッ 詳しくは知らないが➡
You don't have the details,
知ってることもあるってわけだ。
but you have some idea
of what's going on.
めんどくせえが やっぱ俺たち➡
What a drag…
I guess it means
we'll have to fight it out…
やり合わなくちゃならねえか？
互いの思いが違うのであれば
それもしかたないな。
If we're at odds with each other…
there's no other way.
仲間だな。
One of yours?
あぁ ３人に１匹。
Yeah, three plus a dog.
強えぞ あいつら。
And they're strong.
俺たちが劣勢になるとでも…。
Are you implying that we're weak?
(赤丸)ワン！ ワン！
(キバ)シカマル！ チョウジ！ いの！
Shikamaru! Choji! Ino!
よぉ！
待ってたわよ。
Hey.
We were waiting for you.
遅かったじゃねえか。
(キバ)あぁ ちょっとあってな。
You're late.
Oh, we ran into some trouble.
誰か いなかったか？
いいや。
Wasn't someone else just here?
No…
うん。
ずっと 私たちだけ。
It's just been us all this time…
おかしいな。 別のやつのにおいが
いくつかしてたんだけどな。
Strange…
I caught scent of a few others…
(シカマル)そうか？
Oh, really?
(シノ)それより
これからどうする？ シカマル。
Anyway…
What do we do, Shikamaru?
そうだ！
Yeah! That's why
we rushed over here!
そのために まずはここに
すっ飛んで来たんじゃねえか。
(ヒナタ)うん シカマル君をリーダーにって。
Yes, we'd like you to take the lead.
まず 木ノ葉隠れへの
現状報告を優先しなきゃならねえ。
Our first priority is to report
on the situation to the village.
四代目の指示を仰がねえとな。
We need to get instructions
from Lord Fourth.
だが 当然 同時に
アスマたちを取り戻す手も打つ。
Of course…
We'll do what we can to get Asuma
and the others back!
役割分担のために
急いでカカシ班 ガイ班と合流する。
In order to allocate the tasks,
we'll join up with
Teams Kakashi and Guy.
It's a drag…
but let's wrap this up quick!
めんどくせえが
ちゃっちゃと やっちまおうぜ。
(サスケ)こうなったら
もう グズグズしてられない。
We can't waste any more time.
We'll return to the village immediately
and report on the situation.
急いで里に戻って現状を伝えるぞ。
We can't afford any more casualties.
これ以上 犠牲者を増やすのは
まずいからな。
What are you saying?!
(リー)何を言ってるんですか！
We've already lost Guy Sensei.
ガイ先生はおろか ネジまで
いなくなってしまったんですよ!?
And now, even Neji is missing!
And Naruto from your team!
キミたちの班だって ナルト君が！
This all started because
he took off on his own.
あいつが先走ったから
こんなことになったんだ。
あれほど動くなと言ったのに。
After I warned him not
to make a move…
We're from the class
ahead of yours,
僕らは１個上だから
彼のことは よく知りませんが➡
so we don't know him that well…
But isn't he an important friend
and member of Team 7?
でも キミたち第七班にとって
大事な仲間なんじゃないですか？
(サクラ)仲間？
Friend?
(リー)それに 彼は四代目火影様の
大事な息子でもある。
Not only that…
He's the precious son
of the Fourth Hokage.
知るか そんなこと。
Who cares?
任務には関係ないことだ。
That has nothing to do
with the mission.
な… なんて冷たい人たちだ！
How can you be so cold?!
To me, Guy Sensei is
a dear mentor!
でも 僕にとってガイ先生は
大切な師であり➡
And Neji is a precious friend.
ネジは大事な仲間なんです！
I can't just turn my back on them!
このまま放っておくことなんて
できません！
Lee, calm down!
(テンテン)リー 落ち着いて！
Anyway, I'm going to look
for Guy Sensei,
とにかく！ 僕は
ガイ先生やネジたちを捜します！
Neji and the others!
They're bound to be
somewhere nearby.
恐らく この近くにいるのは
間違いありませんからね…。
So there's no way I'll stop looking
and return to the village!
なのに！ それを放って
里に戻ることなんて➡
ありえませんから！
ダメだ。
I won't let you.
We have no clue
what the enemy will do,
敵の出方がわからない以上➡
so we can't split up
our fighting power.
戦力を
分散させることはできない。
We must move together.
一緒に行動してもらう。
うお～！
Oh! Neji, Guy Sensei!
(リー)ネジ！ ガイ先生！
今 助けにいきます！
I'm coming to rescue you!
(テンテン)キャア！
Okay, Lee! I get it!
ちょっと リー わかったから！
私も協力するから！
I'll help you, so please—!
(リー)うお～！
バカばかりか。
I'm surrounded by idiots.
But…
(サクラ)でも…。
お前はどうするんだ？
What are you going to do?
The two teams did
meet up perfectly…
うまいこと
二班が合流してたようだ。
But now, they're moving
in different directions.
でも 今はそれぞれ
逆方向へ移動しつつある。
I wonder if something happened…
何かあったな…。
Can you tell anything specific?
詳しい状況はわかるか？
ああ。
One group is moving away
from the village.
１つは村から離れようとしている。
The other one is frantically
scrambling around the village.
もう１つは村を
メチャクチャに走り回ってるぜ。
That's got to be Lee…
リーだな…。
So then Team Kakashi is trying
to leave the village?
じゃあ 離れようとしてるのは
カカシ班？
Are they heading back to
the Hidden Leaf Village?
木ノ葉へ
連絡に向かったのかな？
It's plausible.
ありえることだ。 なぜなら➡
That's because Sasuke,
who's cool-headed and rational,
カカシ班には 超クールな思考を持つ
サスケがいるからだ。
is on Team Kakashi.
とにかく 近場から
合流していこう。
Anyway, we'll regroup with
the ones closest to us.
だとすれば 村の中だな。
That would be the group
in the village, right?
Yeah…
ああ。
アスマたちを奪還するにしても➡
If we're going to rescue
Asuma and the others,
旗振って走り回られてちゃ
目立ってしようがない。
the last thing we need is someone
making a fuss and standing out!
(シカマル)まずは リーをなだめるか。
We need to go and
calm Lee down first.
Now, follow me…
さあ ついてくるがいい。
If you want to discover
the true nature of the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉隠れの
本質を知りたければな。
えっ!?
What is this?! What's going on?
なんだ!? なんだこれは。
Old Man Third! And…
三代目のじいちゃん それに➡
この人たちは 何なんだってばよ！
Who are the others?
Hey, hey, Neji?
なあ なあ ネジってばよ。
静かにしろ！
Be quiet!
You can make
all the noise you want.
いくら騒いでもかまわん。
すべては かつて
木ノ葉隠れの里で起こった➡
These are just images
of past occurrences
in the Hidden Leaf Village.
過去の事象だ。
((ヒアシ : しかたありません。
私ひとりの命で里が救えるのなら。
It can't be helped.
If my life alone will save the village…
ヒアシよ そう早まるでない。
Hiashi… Don't be hasty.
日向の血継限界は
この里にとって重要な切り札じゃ。
The Hyuga Kekkei Genkai is
a crucial secret weapon
for the village.
It is your duty as the head
of the main family to protect it.
永劫 それを守り続けるのが
宗家のお役目じゃろう。
But if my duty to my family
しかし その役目の前に➡
results in embroiling the village
in a hopeless war…
里を絶望的な戦争に
巻き込んでしまっては…。
わかっておる。
だからそのために➡
I understand.
That is why there is a branch family.
分家がおるのではないか。
We have no choice,
but to hand over…
よって ヒザシの死体を
お前の影武者として➡
Hizashi's body as your stand-in.
(引き渡すしかない))
Father…
父上…。
あの人 誰だってばよ？
Who's that guy?
Do you know him?
なぁ？ 知ってっか？
日向ヒザシ。
Hizashi Hyuga…
俺の父親だ。
なっ!?
He's my father.
《ヒアシ様にうかがった話のままだ》
It went down exactly
as Lord Hiashi told me…
((ヒザシ : いつも強気なヒアシ様は➡
Where is the strong-willed Hiashi
I've always known?
どこへいったのです？
これは 今までとは➡
The magnitude of this is greater
than anything we've faced before.
事の大きさが違う。
そう簡単には…。
I can't just agree to it.
うっ！ うぅ…。
くっ… ヒザシ お前…。
Hizashi, you…!
Please let me go.
(ヒザシ)私に行かせてください。
お… お前には… ネジだっている。
But you have…Neji!
(ヒアシ)なぜ宗家のために
死を選ぶ…。
Why would you choose death
for the sake of the main family?
You are wrong.
それは違います。
I've always resented
the main family.
私は宗家を恨んできました。
Truth be told,
I even hate it now.
正直 今でも憎い。
That's why…
だからこそ
あなたを宗家としてではなく➡
I want to die,
not to protect the main family…
but to protect you,
my older brother.
私の兄として
守って死にたいのです。
そうなることが 私にとって➡
This is the first time in my life
where I have the freedom
to choose.
初めての選ぶことができる
自由なのです。
I have shown Neji
only the hateful side of me.
ネジには 私の醜い姿ばかりを
見せてきました。
だから ネジには
こう伝えてください。
So…
Please relay this to him…
私は 宗家を守るために
殺されるのではなく➡
I am not being killed in order
to protect the main family.
ネジや兄弟 家族➡
I have chosen death
of my own free will
to protect him, my brother,
my family and the village.
そして里を守るために➡
自らの意志で 死を選んだのだと。
自ら… 死を選ぶことが➡
Are you saying that choosing death…
自由だというのか？
is freedom?
兄さん 私は 一度でいい。
Elder Brother,
just once in my life,
日向の運命に
逆らってみたくなった。
I wanted to change
my destiny as a Hyuga.
(ただ それだけだよ))
That is all.
Do you get it?
わかるか？ あのとき
そう言わざるをえなかった➡
Do you understand how
he must have felt?
Having no other choice
but to say those words.
あの男の気持が。
木ノ葉隠れにおいて
彼が死なねばならない➡
He had to die for
the Hidden Leaf Village.
運命を変えることはできない。
It was a fate
he could not change.
かろうじて
最後に残された自由は➡
The one sliver of freedom he had
自分は愛する者を
守るために死んだと➡
was choosing to die
to protect the ones he loved.
自分自身に
言い訳することだけ。
違う！ 木ノ葉は
そんなふうじゃねえってばよ！
You're wrong!
The Hidden Leaf isn't like that!
私も それを期待している。
え？
That's my hope too.
今は 若い忍の世代になり➡
It's now the era of
the younger generation…
and I hope there is change.
何かが 変わっているのでは
ないかと。
あっ ああ…。
H-Huh?
However…
しかし お前たちは すでに➡
You are already bound
hand and foot
木ノ葉隠れの掟に
がんじがらめになっていた。
to the code of the Hidden Leaf.
若い忍にも 里の未来にも。
You have no choice
over your future
or the future of the village.
里の未来を変える 選択の余地など
ないことがわかった。
I know that now.
そんなことはねえってば…。
That's not true, you—!
それがわかったとして
どうするつもりだ？
And now that you know…
What will you do?
里の内側から
変えられないのなら➡
If the village cannot be changed
from the inside,
there's nothing left but to force
a change from the outside.
外から力ずくで
変えるしかない。
What do you say?
どうだ？ 私に
ついてくる気はないか？
Would you like to follow me?
ネジ… まさか！
Neji! You're not thinking of—!
(自来也)こんなところに
隠れておるとはのう。
Imagine finding you here…hiding.
ハッ 久しぶりだのう 大蛇丸。
It's been a long time…
Orochimaru.
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
今日も 皆さんに
喜んでいただける歌を➡
選んだつもりです。
どうぞ最後まで
ごゆっくり ご覧ください。
今回のオープニングは
男・女 うた世界をテーマに➡